Welcome to the another video for section, so we are in a persistent section, this is
another side of persistence, so I just teach how to add the registry runkeys,
start off orders, services and schedule tasks, but if you see really a
persistence mechanism for a threat actor, so if you refer in my turn, so there
will be a persistence called create account, okay, so the creating and
modify the system process services or a second secondary one, schedule task,
job, okay, so if you see in my turn techniques and a tactic under a
persistent tactic, there is a technique called create account, okay, so what is
create account and why the threat actor need to create a account, okay, so the
threat actors, the adversaries, they need to maintain their access rights
inside the environment, okay, so when we are adding the schedule task, start
off orders, when we are adding our malicious executable in schedule task or start
off orders, it will execute whenever the user restarting the machine,
right, it will execute whenever the users or a system are
administrator or anyone who restarted or turn on the machine, okay, but if you see now
our administrators account was compromised, right, so we have injected a
process, we did a process injection and we did some activities, right, in
administrator level, okay, so I did not, till now I did not teach how to elevate
the privilege from normal user to the administrator level, you will see in the
privilege escalation section, that was one of the very interesting section, you
will learn a lot of things about the privilege escalation, for your
understanding, I directly jump on to the different savation, once the initial
access was completed, I executed an administrator privilege, right, then I did
for your understanding these things, okay, if you see the create account, the
administrator, sorry, the adversaries or the threat actors will need to maintain
their access, okay, so if they, for example, we compromise the administrator
credentials, if I am a security engineer for that company, what if I disabled the
administrator account or anything, so you will not get enough access, right, so
that's an one of the important things where you need, you need to, you will access
need to be persistent, okay, so that we are creating account, okay, so if you
refer the mitre to maintain access to the victim systems, okay, so this why we
need to, we are going to create a new account in my Windows machine, so you
will not be see, which I'm creating the user which I'm creating in another
section, okay, because I'm going to remove this user, now I am creating, okay, so
let's move to the machine and let me create a new persistence, okay, create
an account, okay, so how to do that, okay, there's a login called the net.exe,
the threat actor will use the net.exe to create a new user, okay, so the command
is so simple, let me zoom in, so that you can easily see, net user net is a
login net.exe, used to do a lot of things like discovery, enumerations, adding
users, adding user to the account manipulation send all, we can do a lot of
things using the net.exe, we are using net.exe to add a new user to maintain
our persistence, okay, in target environment, let add a new user name called the
attacker, so I'm sorry, we will not find this attacker in other sections, I will
totally remove this user from the machines once our experiment get
completed, okay, so I'm adding the net user attacker, attacker is the user name,
and I need to give the password for the attacker, I'm giving the password as the
A, B, C, D, 1, 2, 3, okay, so this is my password, A, B, C, D, 1, 2, 3,
add, and you can use flash, this is a flag you need to do, okay, so basically we are
using net command and we are adding a new user, the user name called the attacker
and the password is A, B, C, D, 1, 2, 3, and slash add, okay, this command will
add a new user, okay, so let, so the command was successfully completed, so the
new user get added, okay, so now the new users get added, okay, threat
actors use this command to add a new user into the remote machines, okay, into
the target machines, okay, so in this video we have just created the account in
next video, we will try to add this user to the administrator group, okay, so
let's conclude this video, we will meet you in the next video, thank you for
[BLANK_AUDIO]